[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we
have a very serious dialogue for you.
That's right we are going
to talk about a will and
testament, the last will
and testament of someone.
All right so what is
a will and testament?
Well basically this is a
document that someone writes
usually with a lawyer
that explains what to do
with the person's body
and their possessions,
their things after they
die. So many people
write these and the
family will then use it to
discover who gets to receive certain objects
and what to do with this person's body.
Right exactly so that is
a last will and testament.
We are going to take
a look at an example of
once you would see more or
less in English how one is written.
Now obviously they can be very long and
very complex. So we've taken one that has
some interesting words
there that are a little bit
more specific, very a
lot of legal terms there.
So why don't we listen
to this dialogue for
the first time and
we'll leave it shortly.
Last will and testament
of Luke Thompson.
I, Luke Thompson, residing
in California, being of
sound mind to hereby declare this
instrument to be my last will and testament.
I hereby evoke all
previous wills and codicils.
I direct that the disposition
of my remains be as follows.
I'm to be cremated and
taken to the summit of
Mount Everest where my
ashes will forever remain
at the ceiling of the earth. I give all the
rest and residue of my estate to my spouse,
Betty Thompson. Should
she survive me for 60 days?
If my spouse, Betty
Thompson does not survive
me. I give all the rest and
residue of my estate to English pod.
If neither Betty Thompson nor English
pod survives me, I give all the rest and
residue of my estate to
my heirs as determined
by the laws of the state
of California relating
to dissent and distribution.
I point Robert Porter
to act as the executor of this
will, to serve without bond.
Should Robert
Porter be unable or
unwilling to serve than I appoint Jason
Smalls to act as the executor of this will.
I hear with affix my signature to
this will on this, the 23rd of May 2010,
in the presence of the
following witnesses, who
witnessed and subscribed
this will at my request
and in my presence.
All right, we're back.
So now we're going to take
a look at five key words on
language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, the first word here in
language takeaway comes from the
very beginning of this, well,
monologue. We're reading
the last one, Testament
blood. I Luke Thompson,
residing in California,
being of sound, mind,
sound as an adjective.
What does this mean?
That's very interesting.
So he says, I am in sound
of mind and the sound
is an adjective to describe.
I am in a good state
of mind. That's right.
So it means not having
any problems or logical or
unexpectedly. Basically,
I'm not crazy. Right.
I'm not crazy. I don't
have any problems.
We can say this about other things too.
We can say he's of sound body.
Right. That means that he is healthy.
He has no problems with his body.
Or I could say, Marco, that's a really
good decision. It's a sound decision.
So again, that's also a way
of saying good or it will work.
It will work. It's
a good decision.
It's feasible. Yeah. So you can use this
adjective with sound body, sound mind,
or a sound decision. Or
sometimes some people
even say, I think in
Ireland, they say, oh,
he's a really sound guy.
Oh, so he's a good guy.
He's a good guy. He's a very
interesting one or something.
So sound body,
sound mind, sound guy.
Moving on, he was talking
about the wheel and he says,
I hereby revoke all previous
wheels and kata sills.
The verb here is too
revoke, too revoke.
This is something that
a lot of people here
in America when they
drive their car too fast.
Yeah. The police catch them and
the police revoke their driver's license.
And that basically means to take away.
That's right, too.
Yeah, to take right
to take away from.
So this man here, Luke
Thompson, what he's saying is,
I revoke all previous wheels. That
means any other will that I wrote before,
it's not good anymore.
Right. I'm throwing it away.
This is the only
one that will exist.
So you can use this word
revoke with many aspects.
For example, sometimes
employees will get
their benefits revoked
by the company because
maybe they don't have enough
money anymore or maybe
they're bad employees or
maybe they were bad employees.
All right. So to revoke
now, moving on,
he was talking about
his estate. So this is very
interesting because he
says, I give all the rest
and residue of my estate
to my spouse. Okay, estate,
it sounds like a very fancy
word. It is a fancy word.
Sometimes we use this
word to mean someone's
property, their house,
but in a will, this means
everything the person
owns, house, car, things,
pets, stocks, investments,
the estate is essentially
everything the person
owns as a kind of one unit.
Right, exactly. So anything
that is yours or you
may have bought, just consider
the estate is a big bag, right?
That's your estate. And inside this bag is
everything that you own. You might see
advertisements, in fact,
in America or in England
for estate sales. This
means that when someone
passes away when they die,
their family will sell their things.
And this is in a state sale. You
can find beautiful, interesting things.
Right. Exactly.
Very interesting.
So that is a person's estate.
Now, remember this is in the
legal terms because
you also have other things
like real estate and as you
mentioned, which would
be a house, right? Okay.
Now apart from his, from
his estate, he was
telling everyone as to how
they should take care of his body or what
they should do with it. And he said, well,
I am to be cremated.
Okay. This is important.
When a person dies, there
are generally two options.
Their body can be buried
in a casket in the ground.
That means they're
put in the earth.
But a lot of people
choose to be cremated.
All right. That means that
their body will be burned
and their ashes, that
means the things that are
left after they are burned, they
will be taken somewhere else.
Right. Like in a bowl or a pot.
Right. And in this case,
that's what the person wants,
he wants to be cremated. So
that would be the verb to cremate.
And then that
would be a cremation.
cremation. And what is going
to happen to all this stuff?
Basically, it's going
to be given away to
his wife to English pod and to his heirs.
This is our next word. What is an heir?
Now, if you notice,
the age is silent there.
So his heirs and that those
are basically his children,
his daughters are his sons. Right. My
heirs are the people who are related to me,
who in this case will
receive some of my things.
Now, is it only their, the children are
also it be maybe any other relatives?
It could be any other relative.
You could say, I'm his heir.
He's my great uncle
means we're related, but
we're not necessarily
father and daughter or
grandfather and granddaughter.
An heir is someone
who is related to the
family. It doesn't have
to be a certain relationship.
And now it's interesting
because from this word,
we can get inheritance.
Now, we didn't find it in the dialogue.
So it's very interesting because it comes,
they're very similar
in spelling, right?
Inheritance and heir.
Right. Good to remember.
Yeah. Good to remember.
You can, you switch the E
and the eyes, right? That's
right. So inheritance is
a thing. You can receive
this. So I received an
inheritance from my
great grandmother.
That means I received
some money or some things.
That means you were the,
that person's heir. That's right.
Okay. Or, you know,
in his inheritance, he, he
received a large house.
He was the heir to a great
fortune. Okay. Interesting.
So again, inheritance
wasn't in the dialogue, but I
think it's worth mentioning.
And I think now we
can move on to four
very interesting items
that we have for you on
fluency builder. Okay.
These first two are words
that we normally read or
hear in legal documents.
And I want to place
emphasis on the fact that
we don't really say
them in spoken English.
Mm hmm. So remember that
these are more formal terms.
Yeah. The first one
is hereby hereby.
I hereby declare. Right. That means now now
with this word with this spoken sentence,
this will happen. I
think we've seen it like in
movies sometimes. I was
like, I hereby declare this
country in the name of
England. I hereby declare
you man and wife.
Exactly. Okay. That means in
this moment, this happens.
Okay. And a very similar
word that we also signed
the dialogue is here with.
So in the will and
testament, we hear Luke
Thompson who says, I hear
with a fixed my signature.
That means with the
action of signing my name,
signing my signature, this
will be completed. Okay.
So I hear with, you have to
have an action not just a word.
Okay. So I hear
with, I hear with
attach my seal. Okay.
A seal is like a stamp.
Very common in the old days
when you have the real letters.
But I hear with this,
you know, I hear
with attach my seal and give
my approval to this document.
Okay. So it has to be
something physical.
Yeah. Right. So if maybe
you're writing like this
very classic letter,
and you say, I hear with
include a lock of my hair.
Ooh, how romantic. Okay.
That's kind of creepy.
But you hear with you,
you're including or
attaching physically, right?
I guess, I guess the modern version of here
with would be attach. Yeah. Okay. Good.
Here with hereby. We've got
another phrase here that you might
hear more commonly at the
beginning of the will and testament.
There's a phrase as follows.
Okay. I direct that the
disposition of my remains
be as follows. So with
my body, do as follows.
So basically, this is a very
common way of putting
this in a sentence to
indicate that you're going
to start to list
items. That's right.
Or give instruction
instructions. So for example, to
make a loaf of bread, do
as follows. Number one,
get some flour. Number two, add some water.
So this is a way for us to, to say, listen,
I'm going to give you
instructions or a list pay attention.
So please do as follows.
Please act as follows. Okay.
Very good. And our last word
that we have here
going back to here with,
he said, I hear with
a fix my signature.
What does it mean when
you fix? Okay, a fix is a word
we have a number of
other words for these days.
So you rarely hear it. It
means to attach or to include.
Okay. So I hear with a fix my
signature would be attach my signature.
Right. I provide my
signature or I hear with a
fix my address or I hear
with a fix something.
Okay. Very good.
Really interesting stuff.
You'll obviously see
this very commonly with
legal documents such
as these, even though it is
like older English, it's
still very commonly used.
I guess that's a lie.
So old. That's right.
Definitely. And I think
that it's worth listening
to today's monologue
one more time.
Think about some of
the words that we've
just discussed and we'll
be back in a moment.
Last will and testament of Luke Thompson.
I, Luke Thompson,
residing in California, being
of sound mind to hereby declare this
instrument to be my last will and testament.
I hear by revoke all previous
wills and code of sills.
I direct that the disposition
of my remains be as follows.
I'm to be cremated and take into the
summit of Mount Everest where my ashes will
forever remain at the
ceiling of the earth.
I give all the rest and residue of my
estate to my spouse, Betty Thompson.
Should she survive me for
60 days? If my spouse, Betty
Thompson does not
survive me. I give all the rest
and residue of my
estate to English pod.
If neither Betty Thompson
nor English pod survives me,
I give all the rest and
residue of my estate to
my heirs as determined
by the laws of the state
of California relating to
dissent and distribution.
I point Robert Porter to act as the executor
of this will, to serve without bond.
Should Robert Porter be
unable or unwilling to serve
than I point Jason Smalls to
act as the executor of this will.
I hear with affix my signature
to this will on this the 23rd of May 2010
in the presence of the following witnesses
who witnessed and subscribed this
will at my request and in my presence.
All right we're back. So this
is a very interesting topic.
Now I wonder within the
will or within the estate.
Do you also acquire
a person's debts?
That's a good question.
Because I know in some
countries you do in
some countries you don't.
I know in like some cases
some heirs have found
themselves in some legal
problems because all of
a sudden they inherited
that person's debts and
what I think that does
happen especially for people
whose properties are
mortgaged. For example if
if your uncle has a house
and he didn't pay for
it with cash he's a mortgage
and he dies and you
inherit this house. You
also inherit the mortgage.
Yeah. So sometimes inheritances
are not always a good thing.
Well I think this
happened more in the past.
There are more
protections and safeguards
for people today but definitely
I mean what is it like an equity?
Do people inherit debt?
Yeah I think most well obviously
most banks when they give out
loans or a mortgage you
are they have somebody
that will kind of cosign
on these things and I
imagine I'm not really
very sure but I know that
if you inherit in a state
that has a mortgage
you are forced to pay it
and if you can then they
will make that other person
who cosign it responsible
if he still exists. I don't
know in these legal
systems it's sometimes
very strange because it seems
like there would
be a lot of gaps.
That's right and everyone
wants to protect themselves.
Yeah so we've got the bank
that wants to protect itself
it gives a loan it wants
the money back and a
person who wants to
protect himself from maybe a
relative who dies and
has debt. Yeah yeah so I'm
curious to know what
our users have to say what
is the situation in your
country? Do most people
have a will and testament?
What happens with debt?
Or what happens if somebody
dies and they don't have
a will and testament?
That's a good question too.
I don't have an
answer for that one.
All right so let us know
and we'll give you guys some
information on that
as well. Englishpot.com.
We'll see everyone
there. Bye everyone.